同学们，你们好。
现在是二零二三年初中毕业暨升学考试
英语听力测试试音时间。
现在开始试听。
事因到此结束。
二零二三年初中毕业暨
升学考试英语听力测试
现在正式开始，请看听力测试
第一节。
第一节：听句子，选择与所听内容相符的图片。
每个句子读两遍。
and life will smile back at you.
1. Smile, and life will smile back at you.
2. You can't bring food or drinks to the
3. Two boys are playing ping -pong.
4. playing ping -pong.
-pong. 3. Two boys are playing ping -pong.
4. People in like having noodles for breakfast.
5. We should learn how to cook by ourselves.
五，我们应学会自己做饭。
第二节，听句子，选择恰当的应答语。
每个句子读两遍。
I want to be a scientist in the future.
7. What's your favorite animal?
7. 7. What's What's animal?
8. Please remember to take your
9. Please remember to take your
9. How do you get to school?
10. I had a cold, so I can't go to school today.
10. I had a bad cold, so I can't go to school today.
had can't today.
第三节：听对话及问题，
选择能回答所提问题的最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
11. Who's your best friend, Cindy?
Helen. Question, who's Cindy's best friend?
12. Hi, David.
I hear, you are going to Lanzhou tomorrow.
Yes, I'll see my friends there.
Question, why will David go to Lanzhou?
12. Hi, David.
I hear, you are going to Lanzhou tomorrow.
Yes, I'll see my friends there.
Question, 13. Lily, could you help me clean up the
Okay, I'll do it right now, mom.
Question, where does this conversation probably take place?
13. could you help me clean up the bathroom?
Okay, I'll do it right now, mom.
Question, where does this conversation probably take place?
14. I feel asleep in class today.
I stayed up too late last night.
You'd better sleep early and get enough rest.
what's wrong with the boy?
14. I feel asleep in class today.
I stayed up too late last night.
You'd better sleep early and get enough rest.
Question, what's wrong with the boy?
15. Hi, Bob.
You're pretty good at English.
How do you learn English?
I like to learn English by reading aloud.
Question, how does Bob learn English?
15. Hi, Bob.
You're pretty good at English.
How do you learn English?
I like to learn English by reading aloud.
how does Bob learn English?
第四节：听长对话，根据其内容选出能回答下列问题的最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
听第一段对话，回答第十六至十七小题。
change the dog food.
I bought it here this morning.
What's the problem?
When I opened the box, I found that more than half of was bad.
Look. I'm very sorry about that.
I'll take care of it right away.
Excuse me, I want to change the dog food.
I bought it here this morning.
What's the problem?
When I opened the box, I found that more than half of it was bad.
Look. Oh, I'm very sorry about that.
听第二段对话，回答第十八至二十小题
Is there an English week at your school, Kevin?
Yes. It'll start on June 26th.
Will you take part in any activities?
Yes. I'm going to take part in the English singing competition.
Are there any other activities during the week?
Yes. On the last day of the week, our head teacher will speak to the whole school
and tell us how middle school students communicate better in English.
I'm sure your English week will be a big success.
Thank you. Is there an English week at your school, Kevin?
Yes. It'll start on June 26th.
Will you take part in any activities?
Yes. I'm going to take part in the English singing competition.
Are there any other activities during the week?
Yes. On the last day of the week, our head teacher will speak to the whole school
and tell us how middle school students communicate better in
第五节，听短文。
根据其内容选择能回答下列问题的最佳答案。
短文读两遍。
about my family.
There are six people in my family, my grandparents, my parents, my elder sister and
I. We love each other very much.
My parents are very caring, but a little bit serious.
There are a lot of rules in my family.
When we are eating at a table, we should let the old eat first.
When coming in the room, we're supposed to take off the shoes.
Don't forget to say hello to everyone.
When we want to go out, we should tell the parents who we're going with and when
we're coming back.
We can't hang out with friends on school days, which means from Monday to Friday.
I don't like some of them.
They're too strict.
Do you have these rules at home?
Tell me something about your family and the rules you have at home.
Hi everyone. Let me tell you something about my family.
There are six people in my family, my grandparents, my parents, my elder sister and
I. We love each other very much.
My parents are very caring, but a little bit serious.
There are a of rules in my family.
When we are eating at a table, we should let the old eat first.
When coming in the room, we're supposed to take off the shoes.
Don't forget to say hello to everyone.
When we want to go out, we should tell the parents who we're going with and when
we're coming back.
We can't hang out with friends on school days, which means from Monday to Friday.
I don't like some of them.
They're too strict.
Do you have these rules at home?
Tell Hi. My name is from class 3, grade 9.
第六节，听长对话，根据其内容填写下面表格中所缺的信息。
对话读三遍。
Nice to meet you, Mary.
What's your last name?
Please spell it.
Black. Just like the color, black.
Okay, how old are you?
I'm 15 years old.
Great. We have many volunteer opportunities for someone your age.
What kind of things can you do to help out?
Well, I can help with cleaning up, planting trees, and I'm good at drawing.
Those are all great skills to have.
We have a lot of projects that need those kinds of tasks done.
We're doing interviews for volunteers next week.
Would you be available to come in then?
Yes, I can come next week.
What time should I come in?
The interviews will be held from 2 p.m.
to 4 p.m.
next Tuesday here in my office.
And Wednesday in school library.
Which day works better for you?
Wednesday works better for me.
Alright, let's meet at 2.30 p.m.
on Wednesday in the school library.
We'll also need your phone number.
Sure, my phone number is 13653297777.
Great, thank you.
Thanks for your interest in volunteering with us, Mary.
We look forward to meeting you next Wednesday.
Hi. My name is Mary from Class 3, Grade 9.
to meet you, Mary.
What's your last name?
Please spell it.
Black. Just like the color, black.
Okay, how old are you?
I'm 15 years old.
Great. We have many volunteer opportunities for someone your age.
What kind of things can you do to help out?
Well, I can help with cleaning up, planting trees, and I'm good at drawing.
Those are all great skills to have.
We have a lot of projects that need those kinds of tasks done.
We're doing interviews for volunteers next week.
Would you be available to come in then?
Yes, I can come next week.
What time should I come in?
The interviews will be held from 2 p.m.
to 4 p.m.
next Tuesday here in my office, and Wednesday in school library.
Which day works better for you?
Wednesday works better for me.
Alright, let's meet at 2.30 p.m.
on Wednesday in the school library.
We'll also need your phone number.
Sure, my phone number is 13653297777.
Great, thank you.
Thanks for your interest in volunteering with us, Mary.
We look forward to meeting you next Wednesday.
Hi, my name is Mary from Class 3, Grade 9.
to meet you, Mary.
What's your last name?
Please spell it.
Black. Just like the color, black.
Okay, how old are you?
I'm 15 years old.
Great. We have many volunteer opportunities for someone your age.
What kind of things can you do to help out?
Well, I can help with cleaning up, planting trees, and I'm good at drawing.
Those are all great skills to have.
We have a lot of projects that need those kinds of tasks done.
We're doing interviews for volunteers next week.
Would you be available to come in then?
Yes, I can come next week.
What time should I come in?
The interviews will be held from 2 p.m.
to 4 p.m.
next Tuesday here in my office, and Wednesday in school library.
Which day works better for you?
Wednesday works better for me.
Alright, let's meet at 2.30 p.m.
on Wednesday in the school library.
We'll also need your phone number.
Sure, my phone number is 13653297777.
Great, thank you.
Thanks for your interest in volunteering with us, Mary.
We
第六节到此结束。
听力测试到此结束。